网络爱好者翻译
[Internet Enthusiasts]
翻译：danaday z脚步z Ldirene
翻译：萌菊 Iris_LL Fluxman 陆修
翻译： 马丁马丁回音山 一高中萨拉赫
翻译： 不会弹琴的肖邦 kvz.
翻译： Franky97 chmso1o 安隅hh zouuoz
后期：Mike Lee
我们肯定能行
Yeah. We got this.
今晚我们在米高梅大酒店 罗伊
…here at the MGM Grand tonight, Roy.
你知道 那时候阿多尼斯 奎迪输给“小帅哥”里基 康兰
And, you know, when Adonis Creed lost to "Pretty" Ricky Conlan,
但他仍然引起了拳迷及拳手们好奇
he was really a curiosity more than anything else.
那是一场史诗级的对决
But that was an epic fight,
并且从那之后 他连赢了六场比赛
and since then, he's reeled off six straight wins,
今晚为了得到世界级轻重量级拳击冠军
and tonight attempts against Danny "The Stuntman" Wheeler.
他将和“特技人”丹尼恵勒进行对决
to become the heavyweight champion of the world.
值得一提的是 其实在上次热身赛中中
It bears mentioning that Creed actually wagered his Mustang.
奎迪已经输了恵勒一辆野马 罗伊
before their sparring session, Roy.
并且传闻说那辆野马将在今晚再次被作为赌注
And rumor has it that same Mustang is on the line again tonight.
好了 大家出去吧 走吧
Okay, everybody out. Let's go.
- 咋样 - 嗯
- Feel good? - Mmm-hmm.
一定要记着出右拳 知道吗
Yeah. Remember to keep your right hand up, okay?
你的左右拳都一样厉害
His left is just as strong as his right.
- 嗯呐 - 是的
- Yep. - Yeah.
你大便了吗
- 嗯 - 嗯嗯 很好
- Mmm-hmm. - Mmm-hmm. Okay, good.
这只是另一场普通的比赛 嗯哼
It's just another fight, okay?
你可以的
You got this.
你知道 只需要三步就可以走上拳击台
You know, there's only three steps into that ring.
仅仅三步
Just three.
但今晚它却像山一样高不可登
And tonight, it's gonna look as high as a mountain.
当你跨过围绳
And when you climb through them ropes,
你便处于孤军奋战的境地
it's gonna be the loneliest place in the world.
在那你将面对着另一个拳手
because you're gonna be in there with another fighter.
他只想把你击倒
who wants to take you out.
那么现在 你扪心自问
So now, you gotta ask yourself,
今晚你是想向他人证明自己
are you here to prove something to other people.
还是想给自己一个交代
or prove something to yourself?
我只求问心无愧
To myself.
没错
Right.
现在 换我来问你
Now, let me ask you something.
问啥
What?
你头发咋回事
What's with the hair?
我打理了一下 今晚比较特别
I combed it. It's a special night.
你不应该担心点别的么 小鬼头
Shouldn't you be thinking about something else, wise guy?
现在 去证明你自己吧
Now, you can go prove it.
去把你的野马弄回来
Now go get your Mustang back.
第四节 场上的选手已经完全厮打在一起了
These guys have really been mixing it up here in the fourth.
比起经验老道的恵勒年轻的奎迪更胜一筹
So far, Creed's youth outweighing Wheeler's experience.
上呀 冲呀 加油呀
Let's go! Let's go, baby. Let's go!
罗伊 阿多尼斯 奎迪职业生涯中最精彩的比赛也许是
Maybe the most amazing part of Adonis Creed's journey, Roy…
注意防守 下盘稳住
Don't drop that guard! Sit.
不 就是今晚 他为了
…is that tonight, he fights…
出拳 出拳
Keep your hands up!
赢得他的教练洛基以及他的父亲阿波罗奎迪
…for the same belt held by both his trainer, Rocky Balboa,
都拿到过的金腰带而进行的这场比赛
and his father, the great Apollo Creed.
恵勒好像终于上线了 我们之前见过这招 罗伊
Wheeler seems to be waking up. We've seen this before, Roy.
恵勒一见血就真的开始发威了
When Wheeler smells blood, he really turns it on.
加油 继续打啊
Come on back.
加油啊 宝贝
Come on, D!
要是三年前的话 奎迪就已经被击倒了
Three years ago, that's a knockout.
但恵勒已经不如从前了 奎迪肯定也感觉到了
Wheeler's power just isn't the same, and no doubt Creed can sense it.
你击中他了 别放松 继续
You got him. Stay on him!
奎迪胜券在握 现在是在不遗余力的在战斗
Creed's on a mission, really pressing the issue now.
一记漂亮的左勾拳
And a big left hook lands flush!
奎迪继续追击 持续移动着出拳 麦克斯
Creed staying in the pocket, Max. Moving, not running.
加油加油 继续出拳
Come on, now! Hands up! Hands up!
两位选手都竭尽全力
These two men are really going at it.
干掉他 唐尼
Tell him, Donnie!
又一记左勾拳打的恵勒节节退败
Another left hook drives Wheeler back.
加油啊 宝贝儿
Come on, baby!
又来了一记狡猾的上勾拳
That was a sneaky little uppercut on the inside,
恵勒因此受到了重创 罗伊
and Wheeler's hurt by that, Roy.
他那颤抖的双腿支撑不住了
Yeah, that wobbled his legs pretty bad.
- 又是一击重击 - 继续锤他 锤他
- Another big shot! - Hold him, hold him, hold him!
奎迪让他陷入困境了 麦克斯
Creed has him in trouble, Max.
恵勒也竭尽所能了
Wheeler's doing what he can…
恵勒倒下啦
Wheeler is down!
恵勒倒在台上了
Wheeler has hit the canvas!
站那别动 孩子
Now stay there, boy!
奎迪教你做人
Creed taught you!
赶紧起来把钥匙给我啊
Come and give me my keys!
起来啊 加油啊 兄弟
Get up! Come on, baby!
起来啊 起来呀 加油
Get up, get up!
- 恵勒试图爬起来 - 1
- Wheeler, trying to get up. - One!
- 趴着别动 - 2
- Stay down! - Two!
我不知道他能不能在计时结束前站起来 罗伊
I don't know if he makes this count, Roy.
Three!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
Nine!
行了 结束了
That's it. That's it.
一切都结束了 麦克斯
And it's over, Max.
我的天哪 阿多尼斯 奎迪
No way! Adonis Creed…
把我车钥匙还我
Give me my keys!
成为了新的世界轻重量级拳击冠军
…is the heavyweight champion of the world.
你知道你刚刚做了什么嘛
You know what you just did?
嗯呐
Yeah.
宝贝儿 你知道刚发生了什么吗
Baby, you know what just happened?
当你想起这个孩子的出身
When you think of where this kid has come from,
对一个拳手来说 那是最不可能开始的起点 罗伊
the most unlikely beginning for a fighter, Roy.
像他那样成长
Growing up the way he did.
能以这种方式登上拳击之巅
to make it to the top of boxing in this way…
这是前所未有的啊
It's unprecedented!
奎迪 奎迪 奎迪
Creed! Creed! Creed!
成为拳王的竞争者是一回事
It's one thing to be the number one contender.
成为冠军是另一回事
It's a whole other thing to be champion.
这是他建立属于自己传奇的第一步
This is the first step to building a legacy of his own,
我已经迫不及待地想看看
and I can hardly wait to see.
阿多尼斯·奎迪的下一步会做什么
what's next for Adonis Creed.
你觉得怎么样
I mean, what do you think?
我觉得
That's…
漂亮极了
That is beautiful.
真的吗 对
Right? Yeah.
但是我们得赶快
But we gotta hurry up.
因为她就快要洗完澡出来了
I mean, she's about to get out the shower any second.
唐尼 为什么你之前不告诉我
Yo, Donnie, why didn't you tell me about this before?
之前我不知道我能不能赢
I didn't know if I was gonna win.
那跟这个有什么关系
What's that got to do with it?
我不知道
I don't know.
这样 告诉我应该做什么就好
Look, just tell me what I should do.
你得单膝跪下
You get down on one knee.
现在人们还做这种屁事么
People still do that shit?
当然你也可以直接发条短信
You can always send her a text.
叔叔 我是认真的 好吗
Come on, Unc, I'm being serious, all right?
我想问 你以前是怎么说的
I mean, what did you say?
对Adrian么 对啊
To Adrian? Yeah.
那是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
那是一个下雪的冬日 我们在动物园里
We were at the zoo. It was winter. It was snowing.
周遭一切都很美好
Everything smelled fresh.
有一只老虎的背上都是雪
There was this tiger. He had snow on its back.
它走在我们后面
And he's walking in the background.
行了 我明白了 我明白了
Okay, I get it. I get it.
告诉我你说了什么就好
Just tell me what you said.
我正要说呢
Well, I was getting to that part.
我说
What I said is…
我问她介不介意嫁给我
I asked if she would not mind marrying me very much,
我说她是我的全世界
which is kind of a dumb way of.
这听起来有点蠢
saying she's my world,
我还说她让我变得比以前更好
and she made me better than I deserved to be.
你能理解吗
You know?
我觉得你能
Yeah.
听着 你为何不让你的大脑当机
Listen, why don't you just turn off your brain.
只遵从你的内心去说出来呢
and let your heart do the talking.
像这样
Click.
你可以的
You'll do good.
让大脑当机吗 是的
Turn my brain off? Yeah.
明白了 嗯哼
Okay. Mmm-hmm.
好的 好的 怎样
All right. All right. All right.
好的 我准备好了
All right, I'm on it.
叔叔 怎么
Hey, Unc. Mmm.
你还好吗
You good?
是的 好着呢 谢谢你
Yeah, real good. Thank you.
好极了 那就好
Great. All right.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
B 听我说
Listen, B.
我们已经在一起好几年了
I know we've been dating for a few years now,
我们之间还差了点什么
and it's just something about us that just click.
我不知道怎么解释
I don't know how to explain it,
但当你在我身边的时候我会有一种感觉
but the feeling I get when you're by my side is a feeling.
就是我不能没有你
that I can't live without you.
我知道这有点疯狂 但是 听我说
I know I sound crazy, but, look,
我觉得我想说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is…
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
宝贝 我还有点饿
I'm still hungry, babe,
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why.
唐 你是认真的吗？
Are you for real, D?
当然是认真的
Yeah, I'm for real.
不 别开玩笑了
No, stop playin'.
我没在开玩笑
I ain't playin'.
刚才你一句都没听到么
You didn't hear any of that?
没听到什么
None of what?
没听到什么 唐
None of what, D?
你说了什么
What did you say?
我想你已经知道了
Nothing that you don't already know.
提醒我一下
Remind me.
我刚才说 我爱你
I said that I love you,
我需要你
and that I need you.
唐 你知道你现在在做什么吗
D, do you know what you're doing right now?
我 呃 有点
I mean, yeah, kind of.
有点 是什么意思
What do you mean, "kind of"?
宝贝
Babe!
我想说
I mean…
为了和你真正的在一起 B
To keep it real with you, B.
你是唯一一个
you're the only person.
我想分享每时每刻的人
I wanna share my moments with.
所以 Bianca Taylor
So, Bianca Taylor,
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
哟
Yo.
哟 是答应的意思吗 对
"Yo"? Is that a yes? Yes.
答应我了吗
It's yes?
对
Yes!
我愿意
Yeah.
维克托
Viktor.
我们的小鬼头看起来很好嘛
Our boy's looking good.
我相信你已经听闻那好消息了
I'm sure you heard the good news.
是时候了
It's time.
你想过回洛杉矶吗
You ever thought about going back to LA?
拜托 你是个费城女孩
Please, you're a Philly girl.
嗯 应该吧 但是
Yeah, I guess, but…
有更多的空间会更好
it'd be nice to have more space.
你妈在外面
And your mom's out there…
它们也贴上标签
And them labels, too.
这能帮我把我的音乐传播给更多的人
Could help me get my music out to more people.
嗯
Hmm.
我不知道 我在费城已经尽自己所能了
I don't know, I feel like I've done everything I could in Philly.
你能理解吗
You know?
时间不站在我这一边 你能理解吗
Time ain't exactly on my side, you know?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
那洛基怎么办
What about Rocky?
洛基有他自己的生活 唐
Rocky has his life, D.
我们也该开始我们自己的了
We gotta start ours.
今天真冷啊 艾德里安 真的冷啊
It's a cold one today, Adrian, that's for sure.
我好几次想给我们的儿子博比打电话
I tried calling our son Bobby a few times.
但是每次他快要接起来的时候我都挂断了
But I'd hang up every time he was about to pick up.
因为 跟你说实话 我不知道该和他说什么
because, to tell you the truth, I didn't know what to say to him.
如果他有了新的生活
What if he's moving on,
我这个老东西却要紧追不舍吗
and I'm like this chunk of yesterday trying to be today?
而且我也融入不了
I just don't fit in.
我是说 我该怎么做
I mean, what am I supposed to do?
敲敲他家的门 然后说 嘿 最近怎么样
Knock on his door and say, "Hey, how you doing?
这些年都过的怎么样啊 我不知道
What's it been, a lot of years?" I don't know.
想你
I miss you.
自从你有了这东西你就一直很兴奋
You've been hype ever since you got this jawn.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
看看你脸上的笑吧
That smile right there.
你笑得那么开心
You're cheezin'.
这是我爸唯一留给我的东西
It's the only thing my pops left me.
我是说 还有我这双手
I mean, that and these hands.
- 你从来没和我说过 - 是啊
- You never told me that. - Yeah.
你这些小秘密是怎么回事 Don
What's up with you and these secrets, Don?
最近怎么样 挺好 挺好
How're you doing? All right, all right.
你看看这个 这儿
But look at this, here.
- 你好 - 嗨
- How you doing? - Hey.
- 嗨 伊莎贝尔 - 嗨 罗克
- Hey, Isabelle. - Hey, Rock.
嘿 我跟你说 有个大个子坐在那儿等你呢
Hey, listen. Some big guy's sitting over there, waiting for you.
他说你会知道他是谁
He said you'll know who he is.
哟 冠军
Yo, champ.
你得去打那场比赛 伙计 让那个家伙闭嘴
You gotta take that fight, man. Shut this dude up.
哦不 Wheeler还在说那些废话吗 要重赛还太早
No, Wheeler still talking shit? It's a little early for a rematch,
兄弟
bro.
嘿 开下电视
Hey, turn the TV up.
悲剧般的过去把他们的人生联系了起来
…and the tragic history that connects them.
是你吗
That you?
照片不错
Nice pictures.
嗯 还行吧
Yeah, they're okay.
没有我的照片
No pictures of me.
是啊 这里没有那种照片
No, there's no pictures of that.
你怎么在费城
Why are you in Philly?
你不知道吗
You don't know?
乌克兰拳击手维克托·德拉戈今日现身费城
Ukrainian boxer Viktor Drago appeared today in Philadelphia.
向最近摘冠的
to issue a very public challenge.
重量级冠军阿多尼斯·奎迪发起公开挑战
to recently crowned heavyweight champion Adonis Creed.
刚刚 拳击赛承办人巴迪·马塞尔召开新闻发布会
A press conference was held earlier by boxing promoter Buddy Marcelle.
我们来到费城是要让你们知道 我们是认真的
We came all the way to Philly to let you know it's serious.
现在 坐在这里的这个男人 他不是丹尼·惠勒
Now, this man here, he ain't no Danny Wheeler.
说句实话 奎迪三年前就应该跟他打的
And let's be honest, Creed fought him three years too late, anyway.
赢得太简单了
Easy match.
这个国家的人喜欢你
People in this country love you.
但是在俄罗斯
But Russia,
没有人敢惹Drago家的人
no one touch Drago name.
那天晚上一切都变了
Everything changed that night.
嘿 你知道的 这都是
Look, you know, that's like.
很久很久以前的事情了
a million years ago.
对我来说就像是昨天一样
Like yesterday to me.
所以你来是就为了告诉我这个吗
So, you came all the way over here to tell me that?
就在阿波罗·奎迪 的儿子刚刚获得金腰带后
It's no coincidence that Ivan Drago's son shows up.
伊万·德拉戈的儿子立刻现身 这绝不是巧合
right after Apollo Creed's son claims the belt.
这是奎迪对德拉戈的对决
This is Creed versus Drago.
这是全世界都想要看到的比赛
This is the fight the whole world wants to see.
这是奎迪应该接受的比赛
And this is the fight he should take.
除非他害怕历史重演
Unless he's afraid of history repeating itself.
在1985年上演的那场令人震惊的比赛中
That history being the infamous 1985 match.
拳击传说阿波罗·奎迪 被俄罗斯战士
in which boxing legend Apollo Creed was killed by Russian fighter.
伊万·德拉戈打死
Ivan Drago.
阿波罗的教练洛基·巴尔博亚受到强烈指责
Apollo's trainer Rocky Balboa was heavily criticized.
因为他没能阻止那场战斗
for failing to stop that fight.
唐 亲爱的
D. Baby.
这是场炒作
It's a publicity stunt.
别担心
Don't worry about that.
别忘了
And let's not forget,
那年晚些时候 巴尔博亚在俄罗斯打败了德拉戈
later that year, Balboa defeated Drago in his own backyard, Russia.
因为你 我失去了一切
Because of you, I lose everything.
国家
Country.
尊重
Respect.
妻子
Wife.
你见过乌克兰的野狗吗
You ever see stray dogs in Ukraine?
他们几天都吃不上饭
They go for days with no food.
人们冲它们吐吐沫 它们什么都没有
People spit on them. They have nothing.
没有家
No home.
只有战斗才能生存下去
Only will to survive, to fight.
我有个儿子
I have son.
他知道的
All he knows.
只有拳击
is this.
我的儿子会打败你家那个男孩
My son will break your boy.
我今天很累了
Been a long day.
我想咱们就到此为止吧
I think we're done here.
因为在这儿 我们会把野狗赶出去
Because around here we put strays away.
这是张好照片
It's good picture.
我就觉得你会在这里
I kind of figured you'd be here.
你知道吗 我一遍一遍给你打电话
You know, I tried calling and calling, but nobody picked up or.
但没人接
anything.
你不觉得 刚比完赛就训练有点早吗
Kind of early to be training, don't you think, after a fight?
我就是想清醒一下头脑
Just trying to clear my head.
我懂
I get that.
这肯定比心理医生便宜
Cheaper than a shrink, that's for sure.
嘿 唐尼 好吧 我已经听说了
Hey, Don, come on. I heard what's going on.
但是你不能让他们扰乱你的内心
But you can't let them get inside.
我了解你的心情
But I know how you're feeling.
- 哦 你了解吗 - 是的 我了解
- Oh, do you? - Yeah, I do.
那是很久之前发生的事了 你不要太在意
What happened a long time ago, that ain't got nothing to do with you.
听着 那场决斗是阿波罗想要的 明白吗
Listen, that fight is what Apollo wanted, all right?
那本不该发生的
It shouldn't have happened.
但它发生了
But it did.
那么你要想开
And you gotta let it go.
别这样折腾自己
Come on.
但你见过他战斗不是吗
You've seen him fight, though?
我在体育频道之类的电视节目见过他
I've seen him on sports TV and stuff like that.
他块头大 但很僵硬
He's big, but he's raw.
他不像你 你是一台战斗机器 这是肯定的
He ain't no mean machine like you are, that's for sure.
你知道吗
You know what?
我要让你振作起来 因为今天是你的幸运日
I'm gonna cheer you up, 'cause today's gonna be your lucky day.
对你而言圣诞节提前来了
Christmas just came early for you,
因为我会为你背黑锅 幸运男
'cause I'm gonna hold the bag, lucky guy.
- 不 你才是那个幸运的人 - 这为啥
- No, you're the one who's lucky. - How's that?
因为我会让你给我背黑锅
'Cause I'm gonna let you hold the bag for me.
对 这样更好
That's it. That's better.
奎迪被爆揍 这场比赛很快会结束
Creed taking major hits. This could be over soon.
奎迪倒下啦 他可能伤的有些重
Creed is down! And he could be badly hurt.
阿波罗在台阶上无情地看着
Apollo on the floor looking unresponsive.
情况不妙
This doesn't look good.
他彻底不动了
There is no movement.
我的眼睛闪闪发光 我还年轻
♪ Glitter in my eyes And I was young ♪
我清楚离家出走他们会怎样议论
♪ Know what they say I ran away from home ♪
谢谢你 我认清了这个世界
♪ I thank you I learned the world ♪
别人认为我是个心碎的女孩
♪ They think I'm a broken girl ♪
我想我爱上了失落
♪ I think I'm in love with lost ♪
真好听
Amazing voice.
我心碎了 但至少被唤醒了
♪ My heart cracked But at least it's touched ♪
对于演出我很抱歉
Sorry for the theatrics.
但人们喜欢精彩的表演
But people like a good show.
哥们 你那种举动很卑鄙
That was a grimy move, brah.
我不是有意那样的
Ain't nothing personal.
我可不为拳击项目而自豪
Can't say I'm proud of what our sport's become,
但那就是这个项目的本质
but that's the game.
随你怎么说
Call it whatever you want.
对我来说你就是为了钱才这么做的
Sounds to me like you just trying to get paid.
钱可是有负面影响的
The money is a side effect.
罗马不可能自己建成
"The Rumble in the Jungle" didn't just manifest itself.
必须有人去做这件事让它发生
Somebody had to make it happen.
不然它会存在吗
Will it into existence.
呵呵 那个人就应该是你 是吧
Oh, yeah, that's supposed to be you, huh?
你还看到别人站在这关心你嘛
You see anybody else standing here with a care in their heart?
我和你目的是一样的
I want the same thing you want.
你说说看是啥
What's that?
在拳击的历史中
In the history of boxing,
一共有77个重量级冠军
there have been 77 heavyweight champions.
你知道不
You know that?
但你觉得老百姓知道多少个
But how many do you think they know?
四个
Four?
五个
Five?
光有金腰带可不够
The belt ain't enough.
你需要一个故事 才能让你永垂不朽
You need a narrative. Something that sticks to the ribs.
你爸他懂
Your dad, he knew that.
帮自己一个忙 哥们儿
Do yourself a favor, brah,
别想着劝服我了
and quit while you ahead.
自我保护
Self-preservation.
至少你这点比你爹做的好
At least you got that over your old man.
你脑子里肯定都是洛基的鬼话
That must be Rocky whispering in your ear.
我认真的
I'm serious.
真好听
Amazing voice.
谢了 菲尔摩尔
thank you, Fillmore.
真的谢谢你
For real though, thank you.
最近怎么样孩子
How you doing, kid?
我们需要谈谈
We gotta talk.
边散步边聊顺便透透气
Let's take a walk and get some air.
好吗 房子里有些闷
Okay? Kind of stuffy in here.
看那盏灯
Look at that light.
那玩意儿坏了好几年了
That thing's been broken for a couple of years.
弄得我强迫症犯了
It's driving me crazy.
永远指望不上有人来修
City won't fix it or nothing.
灯亮着多好啊
What good is a light.
但那不亮 对吧
that don't light, right?
有意思 但那也一样蠢
Kind of funny, but it's stupid, too.
我要出趟远门
I gotta take the fight.
为啥
Why?
那些人杀了我爸
These dudes killed my pops.
现在他们到处瞎逛 净说瞎话
Now they're parading around, talking shit?
我不能让他们继续下去了
I can't let that slide.
我是冠军对吧
I'm the champ, right?
是
Yeah.
所以我没得选
So I ain't got a choice.
选择
Choice?
你爸也说过同样的话
That's the same thing your father said,
然后他死在那里 我就抱着他
and he died right here, in my hands.
看看他的选择让你妈遭受了些什么
Look what his choice put your mother through.
你不想让这再发生一遍 对吧 孩子
You don't wanna really bring all that stuff up again, do you, kid?
我以为你会懂我的
I thought you would get it.
如果我不去 我会永远活在羞辱里
If I don't take this fight, I gotta live with it right now.
那人是被仇恨养大的 你懂我意思吗
That kid was raised in hate, you know what I'm talking about?
你不一样 所以别去
You weren't. Don't do it.
- 但你做了 - 那不一样
- But you did. - It's different.
有什么不一样吗
It was different?
大不一样
It's a lot different.
那晚应该是我和德拉戈在擂台上
I was supposed to be in there with Drago that night.
而不是你父亲
and not your father.
我本可以停止比赛
And I could've thrown in the towel,
但我没有
but I didn't.
那带给我的愧疚将会伴我终生
And I gotta live with that.
后来我再进入赛场
And when I did get in that ring,
那家伙毁了我的信念
that guy broke things in me.
永远不能再恢复了
that ain't never been fixed.
这么做不值得
It's not worth it.
一点也不值
Not at all.
你为什么要和他打
Why do you wanna fight?
你在说什么呢 我刚告诉过你了
What are you talking about? I just told you why.
不 你没有 唐尼
No, you didn't, Donnie.
你为什么要和他打
Why do you wanna fight?
我知道他们为什么要和你打
I get why they wanna fight you.
我知道他们在为什么而战
I know what they're fighting for.
那你呢
What about you?
听我说 你什么都输不起
Listen to me, you got everything to lose.
而他没有什么可输的
He's got nothing to lose.
当一个拳手没什么可输的时候 是很可怕的
When a fighter ain't got nothing to lose, he's dangerous.
我更可怕
I'm dangerous!
你觉得我会输
You think I'm gonna lose.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
你也说过他经验不足
Same guy that said he ain't have enough experience.
- 不成熟 对吧 - 是的
- Raw, right? - Yeah.
但你觉得我打不过他
But you don't think I could beat him.
这就是你想说的吗
Is that what you're trying to say?
不 我没有这么说
No, that's not what I'm saying.
我是说我不能永远都在你身边
I'm saying I'm not gonna be here forever.
你这是什么意思
And what's that supposed to mean?
意思就是你要放聪明点
That means you gotta do some smart thinking.
你觉得我是在犯傻吗 Rock
Oh, you wanna talk about smart decisions, Rock?
你一个人住在这房子里
You in this house all alone.
是谁在照顾你 是我
Who been taking care of you? Me.
是我一直陪着你
I've been here for you!
还有谁这样对你
Who else you got?
听着
Listen.
不管你支不支持 我都要参加比赛
I'm taking this fight with or without you.
我不会支持你的
It's gotta be without.
我做不到
I can't do it.
就这样了吗
So that's it?
你就这样丢下我了吗
You walkin' out on me?
至少这次你不用担心要不要认输了
At least you ain't gotta worry about throwing in the towel this time.
是啊
Yeah.
唐 你还好吗
D, are you okay?
洛基那家伙
Rocky, man.
洛基怎么了
Rocky what?
他不想帮我备战了
He ain't training me for the fight.
等等 你要接受挑战了吗
Wait, you're taking the fight?
我们一起经历那么多
All the shit that we've been through.
他这会儿把我丢下了 真是混蛋
He gonna leave me high and dry. That's bullshit!
他得癌症的时候是我照顾他
I took care of him when he had cancer.
不然他早死了 B
He could've been dead, B.
我相信他有他的理由
I'm sure he has his reasons.
是吗 什么理由
Oh, yeah? Like what?
什么理由
Like what?
我没他也行
I don't need him.
我喜欢这里
I love it.
我也是
Me, too.
我想把那个房间留一小部分作工作室
I want just a little piece of that room for a studio.
当然可以 你说了算
That works. It's all you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道 也许只是坐飞机有点累了
I don't know. Maybe I'm just a little tired from the flight.
我没事
I'm okay.
那我们就别出去了
We don't have to go out.
呆在家里 点些东西吃
We can just stay in, order some food.
不 宝贝 你得去告诉你妈妈一声
Hmm. No, baby, you have to tell her.
你的歌唱得怎么样了
So, how's the music?
Donnie没告诉你吗
Oh, Donnie didn't tell you?
唐
D?
我忘了
Uh… I forgot.
没错 我签约了
Oh. Yeah, I signed.
真的吗
Hello.
是的 公司也开始筹备给我发唱片了
Yeah, it's great. The record label really hit the ground running, too.
今年夏天我要去参加音乐节
I'm up for festivals this summer.
- 恭喜你 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
Rocky怎么样了
So, how's Rocky?
他不想过来吗
He didn't wanna make the trip?
妈 你知道他就是这样
Nah, Ma, you know how he is.
不爱出远门
with the traveling.
好吧 妈
Okay, Ma.
我相信你已经猜到了 但是
I'm sure you already guessed it, but…
没错
Oh, yeah.
我已经猜到了
I already know.
爱吃咸的
All the salt,
头发发亮
shiny hair,
连皮肤也闪着光
glowing skin.
你怀孕多久了
How far along are you?
妈 你以为
Ma, you think…
你以为
You think…
不是的
No.
我们还没有 不是的
We couldn't even… No.
妈妈真会开玩笑
Your mamma's got jokes, okay.
不 我没怀孕
No, I'm not.
好吧
All right.
- 这是什么意思 - D 别碰它
- What's it say? - D, don't touch it.
我不介意你在上面撒尿 我只是想看看
No, I don't care if you peed on it. I just want to see…
我是不想你乱动它
I don't want you to mess it up.
怎么说
What's it say?
有两条蓝线
It's two blue lines.
两条蓝线 那是什么意思
Two blue lines? What does that mean?
两条蓝线
Two blue lines.
也许是它坏了
Maybe it's broke.
这太扯了
That's crazy.
我很犹豫 唐
Hell, I don't know, D.
宝贝 我很犹豫
Baby, I don't know.
你一直都想要孩子 对吧
You did say you always wanted kids, right?
是啊 但我没想到这么快
Yeah, but I didn't say so soon.
我不知道
I don't know if I'm…
我们有没有准备好
If we are ready.
那现在准备也不迟
Let's get ready, then.
对
Yeah.
她告诉家里人没
Did she tell her family yet?
她现在就在和她姑妈通电话
She's, uh, on the phone with her aunt right now.
Bianca真是个好姑娘
Oh, that Bianca's a good one.
我都不明白她为什么同意嫁给你
Why she agreed to marry you, I do not know.
我也没想通
I don't know either.
你能有个像样的家真好
Oh, it's good to have you home.
妈
Ma, um…
那场拳赛
That fight.
对手是
between me.
伊万·德拉戈的儿子
and Ivan Drago's son…
我会接受挑战
I'm gonna take it.
挺好
Okay.
就没了吗
That's it?
我还有什么好说的
What else is there to say?
所以你并不担心
So, that doesn't bother you?
我凭什么会不担心
Oh, you think this doesn't bother me?
你已经长大了
You're a grown man.
我和其他人的想法都不重要
It doesn't matter what I or anyone else thinks.
你想要接受他的挑战 那是你自己的事
You wanna fight this man, that's your business.
我的祝福是多余的
You don't need my blessings.
洛基肯定不会同意的
You clearly don't have Rocky's.
洛基不明白这对我的意义
Rocky don't get it.
死的不是他爸
It wasn't his dad.
这件事改变了我的一生
It changed my life.
还有你的
Your life.
你难道就不想他吗
You're telling me you don't miss him?
你再说一遍
Excuse me!
别扯到我的头上
Do not try to make this about me.
也别拿你爸当借口
And don't pretend that it's about your father.
没有你爸 你照样成为了世界拳王
You became the world champion without him.
可我并不是很想要这个拳王
Then why don't I feel like it?
要是你爸还在 他也会说
If your father was here, he would tell you he didn't feel like it.
不想要拳王
either.
可他已不在
But he's not.
我希望你能一直陪在你孩子身边
I just hope you'll be here for your child.
你为啥这么傻
Why are you so stupid?
别闹
Stop.
多尼 你的小胡子挠的我好痒
D, you're tickling me with that fake beard.
这可是我的胡子啊
The disrespect.
给我和宝宝唱首歌吧
Why don't you sing for us?
不 我可不是你的点歌机
No, I am not your jukebox.
我也不会挺个大肚子 光着脚
I'm not gonna be walking around here, barefoot and pregnant,
还给你做三明治
making you sandwiches either.
宝宝听到没 没歌听 没三明治吃
Did you hear that? No sandwiches, no singing.
你妈妈可讨厌咱俩了
Your mamma just hating on us.
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
多尼 要是宝宝也跟我一样
What if the baby can't, D?
什么跟你一样
Can't what?
和我一样听不到
Can't hear.
你知道有一定几率遗传 对吧
You know it can be hereditary, right?
一切都会好起来
Everything is gonna be fine.
我保证
I promise.
人们都会来关注这场比赛
People are gonna be all over this fight.
这后面有着好多腥风血雨的往事 兄弟
It got a lot of bad history, man.
所有的一切
Everything.
你爸
Your dad.
还有你爸啊
And yours, too.
别忘了当初是你爹训练的我爸
Don't forget that he trained him.
我知道你之前为什么不帮我训练
I know why you didn't train me before.
我没准备好
I wasn't ready.
你当时的决定是正确的
You was right.
对 但这次不一样
Yeah, but this is different.
德拉戈的儿子
Drago's kid…
高大
Big.
迅速
Fast.
强壮
Strong.
还不按常规出牌
Unorthodox.
他是个怪物 哥们儿
He's a monster, boy.
这人身上几乎没有短板
It's a balanced breakfast over there.
你真的准备好应对这一切了吗
You think you ready for all that?
我必须和他打
I gotta be.
你不愿意帮我没关系
But if you ain't gonna do it for me,
但你得为他们做点什么
at least do it for them.
好好考虑一下吧
Think about it.
替他们完成遗愿
Beat what they couldn't beat.
为他们正名
Change the way they were remembered.
这是我们改写历史的机会
This is our chance to rewrite history.
我们的历史
Our history.
他的战绩或许平平无奇 但是相信我
His record might be light, but, believe me,
他很难对付
he ain't no undercard.
所以你一定得照我说的做
So, you gotta be with me.
任你吩咐
I'm right here.
试试看吧
We'll see.
Creed对战Drago
Creed versus Drago.
这可相当有份量
That means something.
你决定应战是因为父辈那件事吗
Did that factor into your decision to take this fight?
说奎迪就不得不提德拉戈
I mean, you can't say Creed without Drago, right?
这是你们想看的
This is what y'all want.
所有人都想看我们打
It's what everyone wants.
还有件事很难让人不去注意
Also, can't help but to notice,
那就是这场比赛某人不再是你的教练了
who won't be in your corner this time around.
洛基在享受天伦之乐
Rocky's taking some family time.
但我有杜克帮忙
But Duke's got me.
他的父亲教给了我父亲他的毕生所学
His father taught my father everything he knows.
速度 唐 只有这样才能打败他
Speed, D. That's how we gonna beat him.
技巧 速度
Technique, speed…
我相信他肯定会帮我做好准备迎战
I'm confident he'll have me ready for this fight.
既然你知道了你父亲和德拉戈之间发生的事
And knowing what happened between your father and Drago,
你肯定会有所顾虑
you must have some worry.
有什么好怕的吗
What would I be afraid of?
这不正是我作为一个拳击手所要做的吗
I'm a fighter. This is what I do, right?
谁是冠军
Who the champ?
这就是我
It's who I am.
看起来不错
Looking good!
Creed Creed Creed
Creed! Creed! Creed!
你比你爸还娇小
You're much smaller than your father.
不准提我老爸
Don't you talk about my pop.
嘿兄弟 我们在这也能打
Hey, we could do this right here, bro.
- 到这来 - 唐
- Step up here! - D!
他帮不了你什么了
He can't help you no more!
听到我说的了吗 在场外他可帮不了你
You hear me? He can't help behind that ring!
傻愣在那 小嘴一张就知道说
You stand there. All you're doing is talking, homie.
你爸也得看你挨揍 知道吗
Your pops can't protect you, you feel me?
不许说我爸 有本事别走
Don't talk about my father! Don't turn your back on me!
你可在我的地盘上 老哥
You in my house, homie!
确保有人拦着他们 我们在更衣室
Make sure they hold them down. We're in the dressing room.
这里是Jim Lampley和Roy Jones为您主持
Jim Lampley here, along with Roy Jones.
今晚的主赛事马上就要开始了
We're moments away from tonight's main event.
Jim 我这辈子也没想到
Jim, I would have never thought in a million years.
我能以另一种方式见证奎迪和德拉戈的对战
I'd witness another Creed versus Drago fight.
做好准备吧 罗伊·德拉戈正在朝拳击场走来
Well, get ready, Roy. Drago makes his way to the ring.
他的父亲领着他穿过愤懑的观众
His father leads the way through the hostile crowd.
你能感觉到那股能量 奎迪 肯定也能
You can feel the energy. I'm sure Creed does.
在他那一角有无数粉丝为他助威
He has a big advantage with the fans in his corner.
保持专注 这是你的主场 宝贝儿 专注才是要诀
Stay focused. You're at home, baby. Focus is the key.
考虑到德拉戈的体型和拳路
Given Drago's size and style,
他也许会考虑用力量来应对奎迪的速度
he'll look to use his power to counter Creed's speed.
别忘了我们为什么要打这场
Remember why we're here, man.
我是冠军
I'm the champ.
阿多尼斯·奎迪隆重登场
Adonis Creed making a grand entrance tonight.
奎迪和他的父亲一样 总是那么吸睛
Like his father, Creed is ever the showman,
还能让观众热血沸腾
and is energizing the crowd.
德拉戈这下知道了 这可是奎迪的主场
Creed is letting Drago know exactly who this arena belongs to.
这也太像莎士比亚的剧本了
It all feels so Shakespearean.
成长在世界两端的孩子 却因一场悲剧站上拳击场 多么残酷
Two sons, raised a world apart, yet inexorably linked by tragedy.
好了 先生们
Now, gentlemen,
我在更衣室里介绍过规则了
I went over the rules in the dressing room.
请务必确保比赛全程文明公正
I wanna caution you to keep this fight clean at all times.
以及记得自我保护
Protect yourself at all times.
规则如上 不得违逆
And what I say, you must obey.
祝你们好运 互击拳套
Good luck. Touch gloves.
互击拳套
Touch gloves.
奎迪 这次上阵没了长久以来的教练洛基·巴尔博亚
Creed fights without longtime trainer Rocky Balboa.
有趣的是 两位拳击手积怨已久
Interesting to see how Duke manages the corner.
而杜克要如何在场角辅助呢
with so much bad blood between the fighters.
看看他
Look at him.
他觉得他能直接把你当场打死
He think he gonna run straight through you.
- 给他点厉害瞧瞧 - 当然
- You show him what's up. - Yeah.
这是你的主场 明白吗
This is your house, all right?
- 是我的主场 - 上吧 宝贝儿
- It's my house. - Let's go, baby.
开始
Box!
现在比赛开始了
And we're underway.
如果只看体型
If all goes according to form,
奎迪应该是个更迅捷更全能的选手
Creed is seen as the more versatile boxer, quicker…
没错 宝贝儿 就那样出拳 保持状态
Yeah, baby, throw that jab! Let it rip!
德拉戈试图打出一记重拳
Drago is trying to land something big.
戳 戳
Dig, dig.
往下攻击
Downstairs.
奎迪展开了一系列身体击打
Creed connects with a couple of body shots.
然后一个右拳打在脸上
And a right hand upstairs for Creed.
德拉戈暂时还没有一次有效出拳
Drago hasn't thrown a meaningful punch yet.
奎迪又一记右拳
And another right hand for Creed.
奎迪挡住了那一拳
Creed blocked that punch.
但还是被打退到了圈绳
and still it knocked him back into the ropes.
我没事 再来
Yeah, we good.
吉姆 奎迪似乎有点吃不消那重拳
Creed doesn't like that, Jim.
可别犯蠢 年轻人 他在引诱你
Don't be stupid, kid. He's baiting you.
奎迪将对手逼退 愤怒地打出了一连串拳
Creed pressing now, angrily rushes forward with a volley of punches.
他在诱你深入
He's pulling you in.
德拉戈一记大力的左勾拳
A huge left hook by Drago!
- 加把劲啊小子 - 奎迪有些踉跄
- Come on, kid. - Creed shaken up by that punch.
清醒一点
Clear your head.
奎迪占据了赛场中心
Creed commands the center of the ring,
但是被对手狠狠打在肋骨上
but there's a hard body shot to the ribs.
右侧肋骨也受到了重击
And another one on the other side.
你怎么了 兄弟 振作点 唐
What you doing, baby? What you doing, D?
德拉戈右勾拳狠狠击中奎迪头部
And a right hand by Drago that knocks Creed's head back.
奎迪能感觉到那些拳头力量可不小
Creed can feel the power behind those punches.
现在德拉戈开始了进攻
And now Drago is on the attack.
出拳 出拳 出拳 举起拳头 继续
Jab out, jab out, jab out. Hands up, let's go!
德拉戈正沿圈绳遛着对手
Drago's stalking him along the ropes.
离圈绳远点 唐
Get off the ropes, D!
别呆在角上
Out the corner!
别这样 唐 离开角落 快离开
No, D! Out the corner, out the corner!
德拉戈右拳猛击直接把奎迪打懵了
Hard right hand by Drago, and Creed is shaken.
正好第一轮告一段落
as the first round comes to a close.
电视机前的观众可能也没想到
I think most watching at home are a little surprised.
才短短开场的几分钟
by how impressive Viktor Drago has looked.
维克多·德拉戈已经看起来如此强劲
in these opening minutes of the fight.
考虑到选手们的新仇旧怨
With the history these men share,
杜克应该是花了大把的功夫
Duke may have his hands full keeping Creed.
帮助奎迪不受情绪干扰以达到巅峰状态
from letting his emotions get the best of him.
什么情况 唐
What you doing, D?
你得按照咱们的计划来 - 我知道
- You need to stick with the game plan. - I know, I know.
调整步伐 注意你的角度 你没有考虑你的角度
Stay off the line. Take your angles. You ain't taking your angles.
我知道了
I know!
如果他给你一个左钩拳…没事 兄弟 保持镇定
If he throws you a left hook… Come on, man, hold the phone on that.
- 你以为我不知道这么做吗 - 是吗 如果你知道
- You think I don't know that shit? - Well, if you know it,
去这么做
do it!
他害怕了
我知道
那么告诉我
为什么他还站在那
打倒他
现在 我们要开始第二回合了 观众们还在呼喊
And now, as we prepare for round two, this crowd is still buzzing.
在第一节最后一分钟 德拉戈打出了
from the vicious rally that Drago brought forth in the last minute.
强势一波攻势
of round number one.
打的聪明点
Come out smart.
当回合接近尾声时 奎迪陷入了前所未有的困境
Got Creed in serious trouble as the round came to a close.
开始
Box!
现在 第二回合开始
And now, round two begins.
德拉戈出击了 没浪费一点时间
And Drago comes out throwing, wasting no time.
- 离边界远点 - 奎迪被打到后退了
- Get off the ropes! - And Creed is backed.
在边界附近 奎迪试图避免这些强力的拳头
into the ropes, trying to avoid those power shots.
该死
Damn.
场面急转直下
Things just got ugly fast.
又一次右手的强力击打 奎迪现在有大麻烦了
And another hard right hand shot, and Creed is in big trouble now.
保持移动 唐尼
Keep moving, Donnie.
奎迪被一记右勾拳打的有点晕
A massive right hand sends Creed reeling.
他试图重新保持步伐平稳
He tries to regain his footing.
奎迪试图还以颜色
Creed trying to answer back.
现在一记强力勾拳直接把奎迪打到了边界
And now a huge hook sends Creed flying through the ropes!
加油 孩子
Come on, kid.
二
Two!
三
Three!
四
Four!
五 六
Five! Six!
就这样 站起来
That's it, that's it, that's it.
奎迪 奎迪
Creed! Creed!
- 你还好吗 - 当然
- You okay? - Yeah.
开始
Box!
奎迪需要拿出一些绝活
Creed needs something.
如果要扭转这场比赛
to try to turn this fight around.
把他打出去
德拉戈一直保持进攻
Drago just keeps coming.
又是一记直奔肋骨的重拳
What a big rib shot!
天啊
Shit.
这两记强力的右勾拳直奔肋骨去
Those were two tremendous right hands to the rib cage.
你可以听到靠近擂台旁边人的呼喊
You could've heard that one in the nosebleed seats.
奎迪很清楚受伤位置 所以他用另一种方式站起来
Creed clearly in pain, as he finds a way to his feet.
他还没有放弃
Not ready to give up yet.
我不知道 这越来越危险了 吉姆
I don't know. This is getting dangerous, Jim.
好的 上我这来
Okay! Come to me!
现在 贝勒斯尝试让他继续
And now, Bayless is gonna let him go again.
不是吧
Ready?
开始
Box!
他立马移动到另一边
He comes barreling out of the corner.
一记凶狠的右勾拳
Huge right hook!
德拉戈试图结束这场比赛
Drago trying to end it.
奎迪在铃响之前打出一记右拳
And Creed delivers a big right hand at the bell.
回去 回到你的角落
Get back! Get back to your corner!
贝勒斯警告了德拉戈 他看起来很沮丧
Bayless restraining Drago, seemingly frustrated…
服从我的命令
Obey my commands.
…因为他快要结束这场比赛了
…as he was close to finishing the fight.
你得给我拿出点绝活 如果没有 我就要终止这场比赛
You got to show me something. If not, I'm gonna stop it.
你还能打吗
Can you fight?
嗯 我很好 我没事
Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
不 我要叫停比赛
Hell no. I'm calling this fight.
兄弟 别叫停比赛
Nigga, don't call this shit.
你没有必要向别人证明
You ain't got to prove shit to nobody.
看看你 你的肋骨好像断了
Look at you. Your ribs look like they broke.
你不能叫停比赛
You can't call this fight.
他在影响你
这就是为什么他们看扁我们
这就是为什么她离开我们
懂了吗
把我的牙套给我
Hand me my mouthpiece.
我的牙套
My mouthpiece.
别这么干
Don't do it.
现在 我们进入第三节
Now, as we go to round three,
阿多尼斯奎迪已经被打的出血
Adonis Creed has been beaten up and bloodied.
由雪崩般的强力重拳
by an avalanche of power shots.
由维克多德拉戈在前两节打出的
from Viktor Drago in the first two rounds.
我们来看看阿多尼斯奎迪还能挺多久
And we'll see how much Adonis Creed has left now,
他试图继续支撑比赛
as he tries to stay alive in the fight.
停止比赛
Stop the fight.
德拉戈打出极具危险的连环拳
Dangerous swings from Drago.
而克里德拼命地想阻止他
as Creed desperately tries to hold him off.
德拉戈仍然对奎迪的肋骨进行进攻
Drago's still putting huge pressure on the body.
快点 快结束比赛
Come on, stop the fight!
德拉戈又打出一记拳 克里德似乎躲开了他的进攻
And another shot by Drago! Creed seemingly on his last legs!
- 德拉戈继续发动攻势 - 加油 小迪
- Drago on the attack. - Come on, D!
噢 又是对肋骨的致命一击
Oh, and with a devastating shot to the rib cage.
停 停下
Stop! Stop!
这是一个明显的犯规 又或者比赛已经结束了
This is an obvious disqualification, or so it would appear.
因为奎迪已经完全倒下了
because Creed was fully down.
就在德拉戈打出那记长拳的那一刻
at the moment that Drago landed that last shot.
- 不 - 你是要杀了其他人吗
- No! - You wanna kill somebody?
- 不可能 宝贝 不 - 放轻松 放轻松
- No way, baby. No! - Easy, easy!
- 不 不 不 - 拜托
- No. No, no, no! - Come on.
不可能 - 冷静一下
No! Just relax.
现在比赛场地完全安静
This arena is completely silent.
观众都等待着
as the audience waits to see.
年轻的阿多尼斯奎迪的状况如何
what will be the condition of young Adonis Creed.
眶骨骨折 肋骨骨折 3级脑震荡
Cracked orbital bone, two cracked ribs, grade-3 concussion,
肾破裂 多处挫伤
ruptured kidney, numerous contusions.
天啊
Oh…
肾破裂 那是…
A ruptured kidney, is that…
他的伤需要休息和时间
His injuries will heal with rest and time,
包括肾脏
including the kidney.
现在 我们不应该只采取手术
Now, we shouldn't have to resort to surgery,
但我们需要把他留在这里至少48小时 作为
but we will need to keep him here for at least 48 hours, as a.
保险措施
precaution.
现在他感觉不到疼痛因为注射了吗啡
Now he's still numb from the morphine.
但过后肯定会有感觉
but he'll certainly feel it later.
- 好的 - 你还好吗
- Okay. - You okay?
没事 我就是去坐坐
Fine, I just gotta sit.
如果你期望…
If you're expecting…
没事 我没事
No, I'm fine.
不 不 说真的 放轻松 好吗
No, no, seriously. Take it easy, okay?
打扰一下 尤厄尔医生
Excuse me, Dr. Ewell.
有人来拜访你 这边走
You have a visitor. Right this way.
比安卡
Bianca.
听着 我很难过事情变得…
Listen, I'm so sorry everything went…
我是不该出现在这儿的
I should've been there.
我很难过
I'm so sorry.
确实很难过
I am.
我也是
Me, too.
我可以去看看他吗
Is it okay if I see him?
这对我们来说有什么关系呢 我们是有目共睹的
What difference do it make to us? We saw what happened.
他们尽了本职工作了
They doing what they supposed to be doing.
我不管
I don't care.
好吧 行吧
Right. Okay.
知道了
Got it.
WBC对裁判的决定没有表示出异议
WBC's not gonna contest the referee's decision,
所以维克托还是没有参赛资格
so Viktor remains disqualified.
重要的是
Bottom line,
冠军依旧属于你
you still the champ.
你休息一会儿吧
I'm gonna let you rest, man.
如果你需要什么 我就在门外
So, if you need something, you know, I'm outside.
多尼 有人来陪你了
Got some company, D.
做得不错
You did good.
我们尽力了
We tried.
我看到你回费城的时候
You know, I watched you back in Philadelphia.
看上去决心满满 我是说 这毋庸置疑
You showed a ton of heart. I mean, there's no doubt about it.
- 决心满满 - 决心吗
- Showed a ton of heart. - Heart?
我特么真的在努力不让自己听见这词
Man, I ain't trying to hear that shit.
多尼 你不能对罗克如此无礼
D. It's Rock.
- 哦 没事 没什么大不了的 - 不 你们俩不应该这样
- Oh, it's okay. It's all right. - No, you guys gotta work it out.
比赛还没开始就意味着我输了 是吗
I lost the fight before it even started, right?
不 不 不
No. No, no.
这家伙 这大家伙块头不小
This guy was… He's a big guy, he's strong.
他完全够得到你 他各种…
He got the reach on you. He got all kinds of…
哦 现在你倒想着训练我了吗
Oh, now you're trying to train me?
想着做我教练吗
Be my coach?
不 你看看我
No, look at me.
看看我现在什么样子
Look at me.
你还在这里做什么呢
What are you still doing here?
在这捡我的碎骨吗
Here to pick up the pieces?
不
No.
你不应该在费城的吗
Shouldn't you be in Philly?
- 阿多尼斯 - 没事 让他说吧
- Adonis. - No, it's okay.
我不想他把所有…
I don't want him to get all…
你们各自保重
Take care of each other.
对不起
I'm sorry.
多尼
Baby.
他是爱你的 多尼
He loves you, D.
看着我
Look at me.
我就在看你呢 多尼
I'm looking right at you, babe.
他是怎么看我的
How's that baby gonna look at me?
阿多尼斯 你真的有冠军的感觉吗
Adonis, do you really feel like a champ?
你觉得自己够格吗
Do you think you deserve to keep the belt?
阿多尼斯 你为什么会接受那场挑战
Why would you take that fight, Adonis?
这是为了阿多尼斯·奎迪吗
Is this it for Adonis Creed?
我没事 我自己可以
I'm cool. I'm cool.
- 多尼 让我帮你吧 多尼 - 我说了我自己能走
- D, please, let me help you, baby. - I said I can walk.
- 来 坐下… - 我说了我自己能行
- Please sit… - I said I got it.
我不知道 之后 这一切就像…
I don't know. Lately, it's like…
他已经不再是那个多尼了
He hasn't really been himself.
我也能理解
And I get it.
因为他正处于水深火热之中
'Cause he's going through a lot.
他也是才开始进行物理治疗
He's just starting physical therapy.
为了让他自己回到正轨上来
Trying to get himself right.
还有就是
And.
他变得…
he's, uh…
十分冷淡
distant.
也不与他人他物有所联系
and disconnected.
现在就好像一切对于他来说都不重要
It's like nothing really matters to him right now.
包括我
Including me.
这就是他的新变化
Which is new.
没错
Yeah.
听着 你要陪伴在他身旁 照顾好他
Listen, be there for him, take care of him,
把你的爱奉献给他
give him your love.
但是 你也要意识到 他现在所处的境况
But also, you gotta realize he's in a place right now.
只有靠他自救
that only he can get himself out of.
他现在所经历的一切…
And with everything he's going through…
他现在所经历的一切吗
With everything he's going through?
你已经涉足于他生活的方方面面了
You've been in his corner every step of the way.
他是个成年人
He's a grown man.
他会痊愈的 由内而外
He's gotta heal from the inside out.
相信我 我知道的 我已经身处于那儿了
Trust me, I know. I've been there.
嗯
Mmm.
能感觉到她吗
Feel her?
能
Yeah.
今晚 德拉戈让非议者缄默 最精彩的是
Highlights of Drago silencing critics tonight.
他在激烈的第一回合就淘汰了安东尼·诺瓦克
with a devastating first round knockout of Anthony Novak.
现在是对麦克斯·凯勒曼进行的赛后采访
Here's a post-fight interview with Max Kellerman.
维克托 你当时被阿多尼斯·奎迪击败 颇具非议
Viktor, here we are just months since your controversial loss to.
数月后 我们又站在了这儿
Adonis Creed.
这次胜利给你的感觉如何
How does this win feel?
谁击败我了
What loss?
补充一下
Excuse me.
你因为阿多尼斯·奎迪取消参赛资格
From your disqualification to Adonis Creed.
但是今晚 你对此的感觉如何
But how does this feel to you tonight?
没啥感觉 但奎迪必须要和我一战
I don't care. Creed must fight me.
- 如果他不想要和你打呢 - 那他就不是冠军
- And if he doesn't fight you? - Then he's no champion.
阿多尼斯 你听着 又有公开挑战了
There you have it, Adonis. Challenge is on the table.
维克托
Viktor!
有什么好事吗
What's good?
只是勉强维持生计 伙计 好久不见了 怎么了
Just maintaining, man. Long time no see, what's up?
没什么 伙计 刚刚被抓到 你知道的 关于房子孩子的事
Nothing, man. Just been caught up. You know, the house, the baby.
你知道这是这么一回事
You know how it is.
是吗 比安卡怎么样
Yeah? How Bianca doing?
她很好 她很好
She's good. She's good.
好 好 好
Good, good, good.
听着 伙计 我一直想和你打一局
Listen, man, I've been meaning to hit you up, though.
领队想知道我们下一步要和谁打
Commissioner wanna know who we plan to fight next.
你不必和德拉戈打
You ain't gotta fight Drago,
但你必须和某人战斗
but you gotta fight someone.
你得保卫腰带
You gotta defend the belt.
否则 它就会空出
Otherwise, it's gonna be vacated.
我可以设置一些 你知道类似调整战斗
I could set up a little, you know, tuneup fight, kind of.
不 你知道吗 伙计
No. You know what, man?
现在别担心这些
Don't worry about none of that right now.
听着 进来吧
Listen, just come on inside.
打沙包 伙计 热热身
Hit the bag, man, warm up.
好的
Yeah.
好的 我去拿我的东西 然后在那里见你
Yeah, I'm gonna grab my stuff, and I'm gonna meet you in there.
好吧 伙计
All right, man.
把你的身体力量放在那个手套上
Put your body weight into that glove.
好的 用力打它
There you go. Lean in it.
是的 我给你打过无数次电话
Yeah, I called you, like, a thousand times.
是的 关于灯的
Yeah, it's about the light.
能用多长时间
How long?
你想具体点吗 几年
You want to be specific? Couple years.
是啊
Yeah.
我是说 装一个灯泡需要多少人
I mean, how many guys does it take to screw in a light bulb?
我不是开玩笑的
I'm not joking.
我能给你们回个电话吗
Can I call you guys back?
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 妈
Hey, Ma.
妈
Ma.
嘿 妈妈
Hey, Ma.
你最近怎么样 孩子
How you doing, kid?
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind,
你妈妈问我能不能出来 因为她很担心你
your mom asked if I would come out 'cause she's worried about you.
我也担心你
I am, too.
我很好
I'm good.
你不必大老远过来
You didn't have to come all this way.
我坐火车
By train.
坐火车三天
Three days on a train.
没关系 你知道 给你时间思考
It's all right, you know, gives you time to think.
你可以看到这些被窗户圈起来的像一张明信片一样的景色
And you watch all these places whipping by the windows like postcards.
这是一次很好的经历
It's quite an experience.
是的 我是说 如果你这么说的话
Yeah, I mean, if you say so.
是的 这很好
Yeah, it was nice.
这真是太好了
This is wonderful.
你怎么把这些都拿出来放在这儿
How you have all this out here.
你也可以做同样的事
You could have the same.
是的 我不会这么做
Yeah, I wouldn't say that.
我的意思是 不仅仅是那些闪亮的奖杯
I mean, not just the shiny stuff,
还有更好的东西
but the better stuff.
过上更好的生活
Have a better life.
做一个更好的人
Be a better man.
你知道 我在想你以前说的
You know, I was thinking about what you were saying about.
关于我最近做了什么明智的决定
what smart decisions have I made lately.
想不出很多
Couldn't think of many.
你知道吗 我甚至不在那里当我的儿子的儿子
You know, I wasn't even there when my son's son,
我的孙子
my grandson,
出生的时候
was born.
我是说 他现在可能长得这么高了
I mean, he's like that tall now probably.
我甚至不认识他 他也不认识我
I don't even know him. He doesn't know me.
这真可悲
It's pathetic.
好吧 你为什么不
Well, why won't you just.
打电话给他
call him?
这并没有那么容易 你知道
It ain't that easy, you know…
听着
Listen,
我不希望你犯我犯过的同样的错误
I don't want you making the same mistakes I made.
你知道我的意思吗
You know what I mean?
所以 你得问问你自己
So, you gotta ask yourself,
对你来说珍贵的东西的什么
what's the valuable stuff?
就像我以前问过你的
It's like I asked you before.
你到底在为什么而战
What were you really fighting for?
我对此很害怕
I was afraid. Of this.
那些期望
Expectations.
成为冠军
Being the champ.
我害怕我做不到他做的到的事
I was scared I couldn't do what he could.
真奇怪
It's weird.
我以前觉得他是我的一部分
I used to feel like he was a part of me.
现在我听不见他了还有那件事
Now I can't hear him, or that thing,
告诉我进入拳击场的那件事
that thing that tells me to get in the ring.
移动我的脚 举起我的手
Move my feet, keep my hands up.
排除任何阻挡我道路的东西
Hit anything that gets in my way.
我再也听不见了
I can't hear it anymore.
我甚至不知道我是怎么失去它的
I don't even know how I lost.
你的想法不对
Your mind wasn't right.
你的天性不会在那么大的一个人上适用
And your natural style just won't work with a guy that big.
你在说你的更好吗
You saying yours was better?
我赢了 不是吗
I won, didn't I?
很高兴见到你 叔叔 我也很高兴见到你
Good seeing you, Unc. Great to see you, too.
我和你妈妈谈过话
I was talking with your mother,
她说你给孩子起了这个名字
and she says you came up with this name for the child.
阿马拉 阿马拉
Amara. Amara.
是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah.
怎么了 这个名字怎么了
Why, what's wrong with that?
不 这个名字很漂亮 但有点复杂
No, it's a beautiful name, but it's kind of complicated.
你为什么不想个其他名字呢
Why don't you think about something,
至少我愿意 简单来说
at least I would, a little simpler to say,
就像贝基或凯特 类似的
like "Becky" or "Cate, " something like that.
凯特 奎迪吗
Cate Creed?
凯特 奎迪 两个C 容易记住
Cate Creed. Two "C's." Easy to remember.
你知道她即将是一位黑人 对吧
You do know she's gonna be black, right?
对的 我都忘了
Oh, that's right, I forgot.
行
Okay.
- 妈 - 对
- Hey, Ma. - Yeah.
等等 现在吗
Wait, right now?
- 放松 - 好的
- Relax. - Okay.
一切都会顺利的
Everything's gonna be fine.
你只需要陪着她 好吗 这是你的责任
You just gotta be there for her, okay? That's your job.
我懂
I got you, I got you.
- 还要记住 - 好
- And remember… - Yeah.
今天将是你人生中最棒的一天 就在这里
Today is gonna be the best day of your life. Right here.
- 现在吗 - 好的
- All right? - Yeah.
你最棒的一天
Best day of your life.
- 我要有宝宝了 - 我感觉就像是我要有宝宝了
- I'm having a baby. - I feel like I'm having a baby.
- 儿子 - 嗨
- Boy! - Hey.
- 你还在干什么呢 - 我知道
- What you doing? - I know…
不 不用在意 快进来
No, never mind. Just get in here.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay, okay.
就像我说的 你需要我的时候 我就在这
Like I said, I'll be here if you need me.
- 好的 - 好了
- All right. - All right.
你知道 我会做任何我能做的
You know, I'm gonna do what I can.
你在这儿已经足够了
You being here is more than enough.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗伯特
Robert.
巴尔博亚先生吗
Mr. Balboa?
- 对 - 宝宝出生了
- Mmm. - She's here.
真好
Oh, that's great.
这太好了
That's absolutely good.
太棒了
That's fantastic.
叔 和你的教女打个招呼吧
Hey, Unc, say hi to your goddaughter.
真是荣幸
Wow. That's quite an honor.
- 让我看看你 - 她在这
- Let me see you. - Here she is.
你好呀 小美女
Hey, hello, beautiful.
护士 所以
So, nurse…
还有检查要怎么做
…what about the test?
暂时休息一下
Relax for now.
我们将尽快做一个听力检查
We'll run an auditory exam as soon as.
你和阿马拉先休息一会儿
you and Amara get some rest.
宝贝 没事的
It's okay, babe.
感谢上帝 这孩子长得像你
Thank God she looks like you.
是的
Yeah, right.
所以 她会有什么感觉吗
So, is she gonna feel anything?
不会 我保证 这是无痛的
No, it's painless. I promise.
好的 现在他们已经就位了
Okay. Now that they're in place,
我们将给她一点短促的刺激
what we're gonna do is give her a series of click stimuli.
大约35分贝
around 35 decibels.
然后检查她的神经反应
and check her neural responses.
大声吗
Is that loud?
正常听力范围
Normal auditory range.
好的
Okay.
现在我们开始
Here we go.
所以我们究竟是在检查什么
So what exactly are we looking for?
数据 棘波
A reading. Spikes.
但是 我们没有看到任何波线或是棘波
So, we're not seeing any waves or spikes, uh,
鉴于你家族疾病史 是很容易担心
and given your family history, there is some cause for concern.
但是 现在才刚开始
However, it is very early…
他们还会做其他的检查
They're gonna run some more tests.
他们说还早 有时候也可能误诊
They said it's early, and, uh, sometimes they get false reads.
让我来问你
Let me ask you something.
如果你女儿确定有问题怎么办
What if it ain't okay?
我不能这么想
I can't think like that.
你知道 我的意思是
You gotta, I mean,
你会怎么处理这个情况
how you gonna handle it?
我不想去想那些
I don't wanna go there.
你还会爱她吗
You gonna love her?
罗克 你怎么会问我这个问题
How you gonna ask me a question like that, Rock?
- 是的 我会爱她 - 好的
- Yeah, I'm gonna love her. - Good.
因为她不会为自己感到难过
'Cause she ain't feeling sorry for herself,
你也不应该这样感觉
and you shouldn't either.
你收到了一个小的
You got a little…
是拳击手套
Oh, it's boxing gloves.
- 你拿到了吗 - 拿了
- You got it? - Yeah.
恭喜
月亮 晚安 我喜欢这本书
Goodnight Moon. I love that book.
宝贝 那是谁送的
Who's that from, babe?
现在一致认为维克托 德拉戈作为
The unanimous number one contender Viktor Drago.
最厉害的拳王争夺者在他爸的老家俄罗斯
has been met with open arms back in Russia,
受到了热烈的欢迎 这非常好
his father's home, which is nice.
但是每个人都在想 奎迪在哪儿
But the question on everyone's mind is, "Where is Creed?"
如果他不快点选择对手比赛
If he doesn't choose an opponent soon,
就有丢掉拳王头衔的风险
he risks forfeiting the title.
对于他 简直不能想象他能忍受那样的生活
and personally, I can't imagine him being able to live with that.
你还好吗
You good?
是的 她终于休息了
Yeah. Finally got her to settle.
我需要出门一趟
Hey, I need to get out of the house.
我应该要去工作室的
I was gonna go over to the studio.
你能在我回来前照看她吗
You mind watching her until I get back?
当然可以
Yeah, of course.
好的
Cool.
行
Okay, okay.
你可以吗
You okay?
是的 我会
Yeah, I got it. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
再见
Bye.
宝贝
Baby.
别哭了 宝贝
Baby, please.
你是饿了吗 宝贝 你饿了吗
Hey, you hungry, right? Hey, baby, you hungry?
我是玛丽·安 有事请留言
It's Mary Anne. Please leave a message.
嘿 妈 你听我说
Hey, Ma. Listen, listen.
她一直在哭 你能跟我说怎么
She won't stop crying. Can you just tell me how to…
你能告诉我怎么才能让她别哭了吗
Can you tell me how to make her stop crying?
听到语音就回个电话 好吗
Call me back when you get this message, okay?
怎么了 小丫头
Hey, what's up, baby girl?
嘿 别
Hey, no.
没事的 宝贝 别 别哭
It's okay, baby. No, no.
别 别哭 拜托 别再哭了
No, don't cry. No, not again, please.
求你了
Please.
别 看 看 看这个
No, look, look, look.
看到这个了吗
You see that?
看 看这边 看这边
Look, look, look.
快看
Look.
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
嘿 别 别哭 没事了
Hey. No, no, there you go.
我知道的
I know.
我是个很烂的爸爸 我知道
Mmm-hmm. Daddy's being a bitch, I know.
你好
Hi.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do?
她是个战士
She's a fighter.
就像她爸
Just like her dad.
也像她妈
Just like her mom, too.
我得再跟他打一场
I have to fight him again.
我不想阻止你
I don't wanna be that person to stop you.
但我也不想最后和你妈一样 孑然一身
But I don't wanna end up like your mom, alone.
我懂你
I feel you.
真的吗
Do you?
而且这也不止关乎我们两个 D
And it's not just us anymore, D.
我知道把这一切再来一遍很疯狂
I know it sounds crazy doing all this all over again.
但这不会是我的结局
But this won't be the end of me.
也不会是你的
Or you.
绝不是 因为我们会一起奋战
It can't be, 'cause we a team.
上次你上场 我们就没有一起奋斗
We weren't a team when you took the fight the last time.
你说得对
You right.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不该让你经历那些
I shouldn't have put you through that.
那又为什么
Then why?
为什么你还要再来一次
Why do it again?
你到底想证明什么
What do you have to prove?
并不是那样
It's not about that.
如果不做喜欢的事 对谁都没好处
You wouldn't be any good to anybody if you didn't do what you love.
你会无法呼吸 对吧
You wouldn't be able to breathe, right?
如果我不正确处理这事
Well, I wouldn't be any good to anybody if I don't handle this the.
对谁都没好处
right way.
但我需要你们
But I need you.
你们两个
Both of you.
我会打败他
I'll beat him.
你最好说到做到
You better.
这事你得想清楚了
You gotta think about this real hard.
你现在有需要你的人在了
You got people that need you now.
正因如此我绝不能输
That's exactly why I can't lose.
巴蒂说这场比赛得在俄罗斯打
Buddy said the fight has to be in Russia.
要么接受 要么不打
Take it or leave it.
俄罗斯吗
Russia?
在他们的主场上
On their turf.
那我们就去俄罗斯
So Russia it is.
罗克 你觉得呢
What you think, Rock?
如果要由裁判判决 那是他们占尽优势
It's a clear advantage if it comes down to a judge's decision.
那我们就不能走到裁判判决那一步
Well, then we can't let it get to a judge's decision, right?
妈的
Oh, shit.
给主办方打电话
Call the promoter.
那我们明早5点动身
So we try to hit tomorrow, 5 a.M.
不 我有别的计划
No, I got other plans.
- 你是说去费城吗 - 不是
- You mean, you wanna go to Philly? - No.
听着 你想很大程度改变现状
Listen, you wanna change things in a big way,
那你就要作出很多巨大的改变
then you need to make some big changes.
你会帮我训练 对吧
You gotta be messing with me, right?
听说这是个拳击手用来
Heard this is a place where fighters go,
你懂的 重新来过的地方
you know, to start over.
浴火重生
Get reborn.
你怎么花这么长时间才到
What took y'all so long?
这都是些很苦的训练
This some wild shit.
是啊 我看着都觉得像地狱
Yeah, sure looks like hell to me.
既然你要重回地狱 提前适应比较好
Since you're going back to hell, you might as well get used to it.
走吧
Let's go.
放手去做
Go for it.
用力
Harder.
再用力
Harder!
继续
Keep going.
颈部用力
Build that neck.
行了 选手上来
Okay, man up.
不用
No.
我不用
I'm good.
这就是比赛形式 脚对脚 适应下
That's the fight it's gonna be. Toe-to-toe. Get used to it.
开打
Box!
用身体接下这个
Take it to the body.
都忍着 别输给疼痛
Take it! Fight the pain.
你还好吧
You all right?
脚放回去
Get back in there.
回轮胎那儿 保护好自己
Get back in there. Protect yourself.
加油 站起来 孩子
Come on, get up, kid.
站起来
Get up.
继续
Keep moving.
很好
That's it.
还剩下几分钟
We're just minutes away from the fight.
这场举世瞩目的比赛就要开始了
the whole world has been waiting to see.
阿多尼斯·奎迪与维克托·德拉戈的再战
The rematch between Adonis Creed and Viktor Drago.
争夺那重量级世界冠军
for the heavyweight championship of the world.
吉姆 这场比赛的独特之处在于
The unique thing about this fight, Jim,
阿多尼斯 •奎迪处于一个25比1的劣势
is Adonis Creed comes in a 25-to-1 underdog,
他是冠军
and he's the champ!
好吧 这会很吸引人的
Well, it's gonna be fascinating to see.
这对奎迪进入拳台的心态有什么影响
what that does to Creed's mindset as he enters the ring.
别去提起德拉戈
Not to mention Drago's.
德拉戈 德拉戈 德拉戈
Drago! Drago! Drago!
他在那儿
And there he is.
女士们先生们 维克托•德拉戈 正在走进竞技场
Ladies and gentlemen, Viktor Drago! Making his way into the arena.
他没有腰带
He does not have the belt,
但是对于俄罗斯人和世界上的许多人来说
but to everyone here in Russia and to many around the world,
他就是真正的重量级冠军
he is the true heavyweight champion.
孩子 时间到了
It's time, kid.
这是奎迪无法逃避的一战
There was no way Creed could have run from this fight.
阿多尼斯是不会退出与维克托的擂台战的
There was such high demand for Adonis to step back in the ring with Viktor.
我确信伊万在多年后重返家乡的感觉很好
And I'm sure Ivan feels good to be back home after all these years.
一路走来
♪ Ran the whole way ♪
披荆斩棘
♪ Ran the whole thing ♪
从不逃离
♪ Never ran away ♪
无所畏惧
♪ Never been afraid ♪
永远不被击垮
♪ Never gonna break ♪
绝不半途而废
♪ Never halfway ♪
我不知道我能否抗住
♪ I don't know if I can take it.
繁重压力让我再也无法忍受
♪ I can take it. I can take it anymore ♪
我不知道自己是否能做到
♪ I don't know if I could do it ♪
也不知为谁拼尽全力
♪ If it wasn't for who I'd do it for ♪
毫无道理 但是可以大赚一笔
♪ Doesn't make sense But it makes dollars ♪
我想所有的钱都任你花
♪ And I wanna spend it all with you ♪
背离世界也要与你一起
♪ Against the world But I'm with you ♪
我将去战斗
♪ I would go to war ♪
不会让你失望
♪ 'Don't let you down ♪
绝不让你失望
♪ Won't let you down ♪
我将迎来战斗
♪ I would go to war ♪
记住你为什么爬过那些荆棘
Remember why you're climbing these steps.
来吧 冠军
Come on up, champ.
这里是吉姆 奎迪对决德拉戈的第二部分
This is it, Jim. Creed versus Drago part two.
奎迪今晚看起来状态很好
Creed looks good tonight,
但是不要忘记在他身上发生过什么
but it's impossible to forget what happened to him.
这是他最后一次和德拉戈争夺冠军
the last time he stepped into the ring with Drago.
多处受伤 最严重的是 肋骨重度骨折
Numerous injuries, not least of all, a nasty broken rib.
还有一个破裂的肾脏
and a ruptured kidney.
这场战斗中一个巨大的差异
A huge difference in this fight.
是他把前冠军洛奇•巴尔博亚请回了他这边
is he's got former champ Rocky Balboa back in his corner.
所有人都相信洛奇
And Rocky assures everyone.
这场战斗将十分不同于前任冠军的那场
this fight will be very different from its predecessor.
女士们先生们 大家晚上好 这里是
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. This is it.
重量级拳击世界冠军争夺战
Twelve rounds of boxing.
的第十二轮
for the heavyweight championship of the world!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
让我们一起准备欢呼吧
let's get ready to rumble!
吉姆 你能感受到竞技场今晚的紧张劲儿
You can feel the nervous energy in the arena tonight, Jim.
奎迪充满勇气的
Creed has some courage to get back into the ring.
和一个将结束他拳击生涯的男人站上擂台
with a man who nearly ended his career.
一个极度渴望冠军的男人
A man who is hungry to be champ.
战士们
Fighters,
我希望这是一场高质量的公正的对决
I want good, clean fight.
当我喊开始时开始
Break when I tell you to break.
当我告诉你回到场角时回到场角
You go to your corner when I tell you to go to your corner.
碰一下拳套
Touch gloves.
洛奇•巴尔博亚与伊万•德拉戈同台
Rocky Balboa and Ivan Drago sharing the ring.
这是30年来的首次
for the first time in 30 years.
如果有人知道怎么对付德拉戈这样的强敌
If anyone knows how to take on a slugger like Drago,
那个人一定是洛奇
it would be Rocky.
你知道你的内脏有大问题
You know you got the fire in your gut,
我知道你将完成你的使命
and I know you'll do what needs to be done.
因为现今的状况 你知道你为何而战
Because now, you know what you're fighting for.
维克托对奎迪先前的战术感到不知所措
Viktor overwhelmed Creed's previous game plan,
我想它在阿多尼斯的脑袋里
and I think it got in Adonis' head.
很有意思看到
It's gonna be interesting to see.
洛奇•巴尔博亚准备如何应对奎迪
how Rocky Balboa has prepared Creed.
因为这肯定会是一场竭尽全力的大战
for what is surely to become an all-out brawl.
准备好了么
Ready?
开始
Box.
我们的比赛现在开始了
And we're underway.
德拉戈摇摆着打出两记勾拳但奎迪闪开了
Drago comes out swinging with two hooks that Creed avoids.
一个强力右拳给与还击
And a big right-hand right out of the gate.
唐尼 注意点右面
Watch that right, Donnie.
当奎迪挥动拳头时 德拉戈有点惊讶
Drago a bit surprised as Creed shakes that punch off.
德拉戈正在猛攻 但奎迪没有后退
Drago is pressing hard, but Creed is not backing off.
动起来 动起来
Keep moving, keep moving.
今晚奎迪在德拉戈身上不断击打着
Creed working a little bit closer to Drago tonight.
奎迪打出了一套凶残的组合拳
That is a vicious combination by Creed.
现在德拉戈用有力的右拳还击
And now a right hand by Drago.
看呐 德拉戈又开始猛攻了
Here we go, Drago applying pressure.
- 离开场角 - 唐尼 快点离开
- Out the corner! - Come on, Donnie!
奎迪设法脱身
Creed manages to slip away.
让我们接着来
Let's get it.
是 怎么样
Yeah, what's up?
现在他俩在擂台中间的地方 你来我往
Now they're squaring off in the middle of the ring, toe-to-toe.
承受打击
Taking blows.
奎迪一直击打他的面部
Creed staying in his face.
时间到 风暴般的第一轮到此为止
And there's the bell! As a wild first round comes to an end.
回到你的场角
Go to your corner.
德拉戈有些泄气
Drago frustrated.
今晚奎迪看起来像一个与往常不同的战士
Creed is looking like a different fighter tonight,
竭尽全力
Max.
- 就这样 D 就是这样 - 好极了
- That's it, D! That's it! - Yes!
好 现在谁还在喊德拉戈
Oh, yeah, who's saying Drago now, though?
看 沙漠中所有的付出都得到了回报 不是么
See, all that work in the desert paid off, right?
是的 你和他打 你让他明白
Yeah, you got him. You got him thinking.
他没有预料到你现在的能力
He wasn't expecting what you're bringing.
现在 他会带着愤怒在下一轮和你打
Now, he's gonna bring the heat the next round,
但是你已然有所准备
but you're ready for it.
他在超负荷的使用自己的右手
He overextends his right hand.
所以你要用右手格挡
You gonna counter with the right.
用左手打他 明白了吗
and crack him with the left. You got that?
向右伸拳 向左打他
Extend the right, crack him with the left.
他永远不会预料到的 他的老爸也对我做了同样的事
He'll never expect it. His old man did the same thing to me.
根据早期观察 麦克斯
One early observation, Max.
我觉得奎迪能承受德拉戈的组合拳
I think Creed is withstanding Drago's combinations.
今晚的比赛比第一次比赛好多了
much better tonight than in the first fight.
开始
Box.
第二轮开始
And round two begins.
德拉戈用一个强力左勾拳
Drago with a huge left hook.
和强力右拳
And a big right hand.
德拉戈再次发起攻击 现在把奎迪逼到了围栏绳
Drago on the attack again, now driving Creed back into the ropes.
他越过了右边 注意右边
He's overextending the right! Watch the right!
奎迪从左右打出两拳
A right and a left for Creed.
强力的上勾拳打中了奎迪
Huge uppercut has Creed holding on now.
德拉戈把他逼到角落里
Drago throws him off into the corner.
- 离开那个角落 - 离开那个角落
- Get out of that corner! - Get out of the corner!
德拉戈把奎迪扔回台上
And Drago throws Creed to the canvas.
发生什么事
What's going on?
第一次打斗的阴影 但德拉戈这次表现出克制
Shades of the first fight, but Drago showing restraint this time.
你还好吗
You good?
是的 我很好
Yes, I'm good.
- 开始 - 德拉戈在休息后爆发了
- Box. - Drago explodes from the break.
奎迪倒下了
And Creed is down!
一阵猛烈的进攻
A flurry of heavy shots!
德拉戈的力量真是不可思议
Drago's power is just incredible.
三
Three.
四
Four.
数到八 等八数完
Take the eight count. Take the full eight.
奎迪仍然趴在台上
Creed taking his time on the canvas.
六
Six.
继续趴着 呼吸
Stay down! Breathe!
他在听之前遇到过这种情况的洛基的话
He's listening to Rocky, who has been in this situation before.
奎迪又站起来了 刚好数完
And Creed is back on his feet. Beats the count.
- 准备好了吗 - 好 上
- Ready? - Yeah, let's go.
开始
Box.
缠住他 别和他打 缠住他
Tie him up. Don't fight him. Tie him up.
德拉戈又开始进攻了
Drago is right back at it.
随着铃响激烈的攻击也结束了
So, with the knockdown and those hard shots at the end,
这一轮显然维克多·德拉戈占优
that round clearly goes to Viktor Drago.
你可以感觉到他蓄势待发
And you could just feel he's gaining momentum.
你知道这会是场战争 对吧
You knew this was gonna be a war, right?
你知道接下来该怎么做
You knew that going in there.
从现在开始 是谁想要更多
From now on, it's who wants it more,
就要更用心
and who's got more heart.
别让他打到你 你和他拉远距离 你会被打伤
Don't let him crack you. You stay on the outside, you're gonna get hurt.
你和他拉近距离 你能把他撕碎的
You stay on the inside, you'll tear him up.
我告诉你这都和压力有关
I'm telling you, it's all about pressure.
如果你想打疼他 你必须能承受痛苦
If you wanna give pain, you gotta be willing to take the pain.
过来
Come on!
- 好 - 好
- Yes! - Yes!
第四轮是残酷的另一体现
Round four is another brutal display.
当奎迪给了德拉戈大量惩罚后
as Creed takes a lot of punishment from Drago.
德拉戈也不在犹豫
Drago is not slowing down.
在铃响后落下打出了一记重拳
Landing a big shot after the bell.
你有毛病吗
What is your problem?
激烈的角逐继续 吉姆
The violent chess match continues, Jim.
奎迪再次倒下了
Oh, and Creed is down again.
唐尼起来
Donnie, get up.
德拉戈掌控了这场战斗 但奎迪也不会放弃
Drago clearly dominating this fight, but Creed will not give up.
他受到了很多攻击
He is taking a lot of punishment.
你必须面对他 看着我
You gotta stay in his face. Look at me.
当你看到机会 就抓住它
And when you see an opportunity, you go after it.
好样的
There you are!
德拉戈的节奏被打断了
Drago is cut now.
我们进入了第八轮
As we enter round eight,
比赛深入到了谁都没想到的程度
we are deeper into this fight than anyone expected.
奎迪必须察觉到他后面 他正在改变动作
Creed must sense he's behind. He's trying to force the action.
好样的 宝贝
Yes, baby!
我们今晚看到的是阿多尼斯奎迪
What we are seeing tonight is Adonis Creed.
面对维克多·德拉戈的强大力量
standing up to the awesome power of Viktor Drago.
他也没有闪避
He's not going anywhere.
维克托德拉戈看上去已经疲惫了 麦克斯
Viktor Drago looks tired, Max.
记住 他从来没有打到过第四轮后在
Keep in mind, he's never had to go past the 4th round in a.
职业比赛中
professional fight.
- 嘿 那是什么 - 犯规了 裁判
- Hey! What was that? - Take the point, ref!
德拉戈打倒了奎迪
And Drago drops Creed.
- 用肮脏的手段 - 干什么呢
- with two nasty body shots. - Come on!
- 他抓住他打他 - 一
- He held him and hit him. - One.
维克多也许带着什么离开了
Viktor holding and maybe getting away with something there.
裁判一定没有看到
The ref must not have seen it.
过来
Come on.
我认为洛基·巴尔博亚在这做了个决定 吉姆
I think Rocky Balboa has a decision to make here, Jim.
他比谁都了解的多
He knows better than anyone.
三十年前发生过同样的故事
how this same story played out three decades ago.
唐尼 唐尼 和我说话
Donnie, Donnie, talk to me.
唐尼
Donnie.
你的
Your ribs?
你认为它断了
You think it's broke?
你想怎么办 唐尼
What do you wanna do, Donnie?
你想叫停吗
You wanna call it?
我不这么认为
I didn't think so.
现在他会向你冲来
Now he's gonna come after you,
而且他会尝试打断你更多肋骨
and he's gonna try to break on that rib some more.
不过没关系
But that's okay.
因为你喜欢疼痛 你能承受它
'Cause you like the pain. You can take it.
你知道为什么吗 因为你很危险
You know why? Because you're dangerous.
- 我危险 - 是的
- I'm dangerous. - That's right.
十秒到了
Ten seconds out.
现在我们进入了第十轮
Now here we go with round ten.
这已经成为一场消耗战
of what has become a war of attrition.
Drago似乎在分数上领先
Drago seemingly ahead on the scorecards,
但Creed并没有退缩的意思
but Creed refusing to back down.
就是这样 Donnie 很好
That's it, Donnie. Good.
Creed用上了全身剩下的
Creed using whatever he has left.
每一分力量在支撑
in the tank.
Drago乘胜追击
Drago working the body.
锁他
Tie him up!
Creed又一次倒下
And down goes Creed again.
可能这场比赛就要落下帷幕
And this could be the end of the fight.
振作起来 D.
Get up, D.
天呐 应该没有人能躲过那致命一拳
No man should be able to fight through that beating,
但Adonis Creed却以信念
but Adonis Creed wills himself.
支撑自己站了起来
off the canvas.
- 你叫什么名字 信条
- What's your name? - Creed.
你还清醒吗 叫出你的名字
What's your name?
Creed
Creed!
开始
Box!
Adonis Creed知道没有办法
Adonis Creed knows there is no way.
躲过Viktor Drago
around Viktor Drago.
他必须正面迎战
He has to go through him.
出拳
Dig!
继续 继续
Dig! Dig!
Creed就像突然装上了新的齿轮
Creed suddenly finding.
动力十足啊
another gear!
加油
Come on!
拉开Drago一大段距离
Drago's on his heels.
然后德拉戈被击倒啦
And down goes Drago!
就是这样 好样的
That's it! That's right!
多么戏剧性的逆转啊
What a wild turn of events.
二
Two.
Donnie 他起来了 过去补刀
Donnie, he gets up, you go after him.
三
Three.
四
Four.
五
Five.
- 六 - Drago在计时结束前
- Six. - Drago beats.
站了起来
the count.
完全不敢相信他们两个依然矗立着
I can't believe either of these guys are still on their feet.
开打
Box.
德拉戈似乎在分数上遥遥领先 他只
Drago seemingly so far ahead on points,
需要站稳坚持到最后就能赢得比赛
he just needs to stay upright and make it to the end.
那个男人又回来了
Here comes Creed again,
他把Drago逼退到了擂台边缘
driving Drago back into the ropes.
继续 出拳 连击 - 棒
- Dig! Dig! Dig! - Yeah!
快 干掉他
Come on, take him down!
加油啊 宝贝
Come on, baby.
Victor Drago倒下了
And Viktor Drago is down!
再一次
Again!
这场战斗发生了如此大逆转
What a turn this fight has taken.
Creed没有向痛苦屈服
Creed doubled over in pain.
当德拉戈试图从地板上爬起来的时候
as Drago tries to pick himself up off the floor.
Drago积蓄力量 成功战胜了计数
Drago summons the strength, manages to make the count.
他们还是有些站不稳 Max
They're still swinging, Max.
克里德依然力量在线
Creed continuing to connect.
这开始让人不忍心去看了 Jim
And this is becoming hard to watch, Jim.
我觉得Drago没有力气再坚持下去了
I don't think Drago has anything left,
但他拒绝放弃
but he refuses to give up.
比赛 结束了
And that's it! It's over!
Drago的教练于心不忍
Drago's corner throws.
扔出了白毛巾认输了
in the towel.
Adonis Creed捍卫他的头衔
And Adonis Creed defends his title.
与他的名字
Defends his name.
告诉这个世界
Creates his own legacy.
他仍然是世界重量级冠军
He is still the heavyweight champion of the world.
俄罗斯人群都站了起来
And the Russian crowd is standing and.
为那个美国拳手欢呼
cheering for the American fighter.
B在哪里 B在哪
Where's B at? Where's B?
放松 放松 冷静点
Easy, easy, easy.
嘿 后退 大家退后 让空气流通
Hey, back up. Everybody back up. We need air.
是啊
Yeah.
- 我们做到了 - 我们做到了
- We did it. - We did it.
没关系的 你做的很好了
很棒了
- 我们回家吧 - 走吧 D.
- Let's go home. - Let's go, D.
我还好 妈 撑得住
I'm good, Ma. I'm good.
- 我做到了 我做到了 - 你做到了
- I did it. I did it. - You did it.
嘿 叔
Hey, Unc.
这是属于你的时刻
It's your time.
嘿 好的 后退
Hey, okay, back up.
怎么了 老爸
What's up, Pops?
很抱歉我花了这么长时间才见到你
I'm sorry it took me so long to come see you.
我不知道该怎么办 嗯
I'm not sure how this is supposed to go. Um…
我想我应该告诉你妈妈很好
I guess I should tell you that Mom's doing pretty good.
你知道 她在坚持
You know, she's holding up.
洛基也是
So is Rocky.
- 非常感谢 谢谢
- Thanks a lot. - Thank you.
他是个硬汉
He's a tough dude.
我知道你为什么喜欢他
I can see why you liked him.
我也明白你为什么想要和他打一场
I also see why you wanted to fight him, too.
听着 嗯
Look, um,
我只是来告诉你 我
I just came here to tell you that…
我做到了
That I did it.
但我不是为你做的
But I didn't do it for you.
或者因为他们
Or because of them.
我这么做 是因为那是属于我的战斗
I did it because it was my fight.
当我踏入那个擂台起
And when I stepped into that ring,
就不仅仅是我一个人的事了
it wasn't just about me.
你好
Hello.
你一定是Logan
You must be Logan.
对 你是谁
Yes. Who are you?
小罗 是谁在那
Lo, who is it?
有时我们认为我们必须独自完成这一切
Sometimes we think we have to do it all on our own.
嘿 Robert
Hey, Robert.
但是我们没有
But we don't.
我就在附近 所以
I was just around in the neighborhood, so…
这是你的爷爷
This is your grandfather.
你看起来就像他的母亲
You look just like his mother.
对啊
Yeah, I know.
我想给你介绍她们
I wanna introduce you to somebody.
你想进来吗
Do you wanna come inside?
好啊
Yeah.
把那个给我
Give me that.
- 那是一个球吗 - 是的
- Is that a ball? - Yeah.
- 想玩接球吗 - 是的
- Wanna play catch? - Yes.
来吧
There you go.
这
This.
是你的孙女 Amara
is your granddaughter. Amara.
说 给爷爷问个好
Say what's up to Pop-Pop.